<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <array name="smoothness_type_values">
        <item name="">excellent</item>
        <item name="">good</item>
        <item name="">intermediate</item>
        <item name="">bad</item>
        <item name="">very_bad</item>
        <item name="">horrible</item>
        <item name="">very_horrible</item>
        <item name="">impassable</item>
    </array>

    <array name="smoothness_type_comments">
        <item name="excellent">As-new asphalt or concrete, smooth paving stones with seamless
            connections, etc.
        </item>
        <item name="good">Asphalt or concrete showing the first signs of wear, such as narrow (less
            than 1.5 cm) cracks, wider cracks filled up with tar, shallow dents in which rainwater
            may collect, etc. that may cause trouble for rollers but not for racing bikes. The best
            roads paved with bricks, sett, etc. also fall in this category.
        </item>
        <item name="intermediate">Asphalt and equivalent that shows signs of maintenance such as
            patches of repaired pavement, wider cracks (>2 cm), etc. that may cause trouble for
            racing bikes. The pavement may contain potholes, but these are small, shallow (less than
            3cm deep) and few so they are easily avoided, or the road shows damage due to subsidence
            (depressions of a scale >50 cm) or heavy traffic (shallow ruts in asphalt caused by
            trucks in summer). The quality of the surface starts to affect the speed of most
            passenger cars, so they will slow down to make the ride more comfortable (but still
            above 50% of the speed they would drive at if the road was smooth). The best unpaved but
            compacted roads fall in this category.
        </item>
        <item name="bad">Heavily damaged paved roads that badly need maintenance: many potholes,
            some of them quite deep. The average speed of cars is less than 50% of what it would be
            on a smooth road. However, it isn’t so rough that ground clearance becomes a problem. A
            ground clearance of a normal passenger car (>14 cm) is sufficient. Good unpaved roads
            without risk of damage to normal passenger cars are also included here.
        </item>
        <item name="very_bad">Unpaved roads with potholes and ruts, but still passable with an
            average SUV with a ground clearance of at least 18 cm.*
        </item>
        <item name="horrible">Unpaved tracks with ruts, rocks etc that need a ground clearance of at
            least 21 cm (Toyota Landcruiser, Landrover, Lada Niva, bukhanka, etc.). Skid plate
            protection is advisable.
        </item>
        <item name="very_horrible">Tracks with deep ruts and other obstacles that need a ground
            clearance of at least 24 cm.
        </item>
        <item name="impassable">Ways that used to be passable roads and can still be recognised as
            such in the landscape (useful for hikers), but have deteriorated so much because of
            fallen trees, being overgrown, severely eroded, etc. that no 4-wheeled vehicle can pass
            it. Consider to map narrow parts as path, and the whole way as disused:=* or
            abandoned:=*
        </item>
    </array>

    <integer-array name="smoothness_type_photo_resources">
        <item name="excellent">@drawable/smoothness_type_excellent</item>
        <item name="good">@drawable/smoothness_type_good</item>
        <item name="intermediate">@drawable/smoothness_type_intermediate</item>
        <item name="bad">@drawable/smoothness_type_bad</item>
        <item name="very_bad">@drawable/smoothness_type_very_bad</item>
        <item name="horrible">@drawable/smoothness_type_horrible</item>
        <item name="very_horrible">@drawable/smoothness_type_very_horrible</item>
        <item name="impassable">@drawable/smoothness_type_impassable</item>
    </integer-array>

</resources>