<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <array name="surface_type_values">
        <item name="paved">paved</item>
        <item name="asphalt">asphalt</item>
        <item name="concrete">concrete</item>
        <item name="concrete:lanes">concrete:lanes</item>
        <item name="concrete:plates">concrete:plates</item>
        <item name="paving_stones">paving_stones</item>
        <item name="sett">sett</item>
        <item name="unhewn_cobblestone">unhewn_cobblestone</item>
        <item name="cobblestone">cobblestone</item>
        <item name="metal">metal</item>
        <item name="wood">wood</item>
        <item name="stepping_stones">stepping_stones</item>
        <item name="unpaved">unpaved</item>
        <item name="compacted">compacted</item>
        <item name="fine_gravel">fine_gravel</item>
        <item name="gravel">gravel</item>
        <item name="rock">rock</item>
        <item name="pebblestone">pebblestone</item>
        <item name="ground">ground</item>
        <item name="dirt">dirt</item>
        <item name="earth">earth</item>
        <item name="grass">grass</item>
        <item name="grass_paver">grass_paver</item>
        <item name="mud">mud</item>
        <item name="sand">sand</item>
        <item name="woodchips">woodchips</item>
        <item name="snow">snow</item>
        <item name="ice">ice</item>
        <item name="salt">salt</item>
        <item name="mixed">mixed</item>
    </array>

    <array name="surface_type_comments">
        <item name="paved">A feature that is predominantly paved; i.e., it is covered with paving
            stones, concrete or bitumen. This value gives only a rough description; use a more
            precise value if possible.
        </item>
        <item name="asphalt">Short for asphalt concrete - mineral aggregate bound by asphalt. Most
            such features are tagged as paved without specifying exact surface.
        </item>
        <item name="concrete">Cement based concrete, forming a large surface, typically cast in
            place and may have predetermined breaking joints. For pre-fabricated plates, please use
            concrete:plates or concrete:lanes if you know how the concrete is laid out and one of
            these tags fits.
        </item>
        <item name="concrete:lanes">Long, narrow concrete elements for a two-tracked vehicle
            (motorcars) so that the tires always hit the concrete. There might be sand, ground,
            grass, pavers, asphalt, etc. in between them. Note that if you tag a single-tracked way
            you just use concrete, since there are no lanes.
        </item>
        <item name="concrete:plates">Heavy duty plates chained closely together on the short side.
            Might have tar or sand in between the connections.
        </item>
        <item name="paving_stones">A relatively smooth surface paved with artificial blocks (block
            pavers, bricks) or natural stones (flagstones), with a flat top. The gaps between
            individual paving stones are very narrow, either because the stones have a perfectly
            regular shape (rectangular, or any surface-filling shape) or because they have been
            carefully selected, fitted and placed in order to form an even, closed surface.
        </item>
        <item name="sett">Sett paving, formed from natural stones cut usually to a regular shape.
            The stones do not cover the surface completely, unlike paving_stones.
        </item>
        <item name="unhewn_cobblestone">Raw cobblestone of natural, uncut, rounded stones. Unlike
            pebblestone firmly connected to the ground.
        </item>
        <item name="cobblestone">Generic value for cobblestone in the colloquial sense. It is better
            to use a more precise value such as sett or unhewn_cobblestone
        </item>
        <item name="metal">Used for metal surfaced bridges, or for temporary tracks over fields for
            normal road vehicles or site traffic.
        </item>
        <item name="wood">Used for wood surfaced bridges, plank walkways, and garden decking</item>
        <item name="stepping_stones">Stones or plates individually arranged in a row, allowing to
            walk on, surrounded by an unpaved medium such as grass or water
        </item>
        <item name="unpaved">A feature that is predominantly unsealed (unpaved); i.e., it has a
            loose covering ranging from compacted stone chippings to earth. Unpaved roads may, in
            aerial imagery, show evidence of water along their course; in such circumstances, the
            waterway should not be tagged as a stream, though it might appear as such. This value
            gives only a rough description; use a more precise value if possible.
        </item>
        <item name="compacted">A mixture of larger (e.g., gravel) and smaller (e.g., sand) parts,
            compacted (e.g., with a roller), so the surface is more stable than loose gravel. Used,
            for example, for park paths, better tracks, some service ways, … Best sort of ways below
            paving with asphalt, concrete, paving stones. Sometimes known as water-bound macadam.
            Mixture and compacting leads to more grip and stability.
        </item>
        <item name="fine_gravel">A multilayer pavement with a stone or gravel basis and a topmost
            surface of firm, granular grit, basalt or quartz, as invented by the Roman empire. Easy
            to walk, jog, cycle or ride on. In hilly areas mostly with drainage channels and concave
            cross-section for proper water shedding. Motorized vehicles will not move stones if the
            way is maintained properly, and bicycles tires will not leave any imprints at least in
            dry weather. If the topmost surface is eroded or loose gravel aggravate please use
            gravel instead.
        </item>
        <item name="gravel">This tag has very large meaning range. Used for cases ranging from huge
            gravel pieces like track ballast used as surface, through small pieces of gravel to
            compacted surface.
        </item>
        <item name="rock">Exposed rock or big pieces of rock used to improve path quality. Typically
            in mountainous areas.
        </item>
        <item name="pebblestone">Pebbles are stones rounded by waves or river flow. Typical size
            range from 2 to 8 cm.
            Describing a surface in OSM they are loosely arranged. Like gravel pebbles can be used
            as a building part of compacted.
        </item>
        <item name="ground">No special surface, the ground itself has marks of human or animal
            usage. This value gives only a rough description; if possible, use a more precise value
            such as grass, clay, sand, earth, gravel or pebblestone.
        </item>
        <item name="dirt">Probably very similar to ground. Like all this, it is prone to erosion
            and therefore often uneven. Gravel is sometimes mistakenly called dirt. Some compacted
            surfaces are sometimes called "dirt" too, please consider the definition of compacted.
        </item>
        <item name="earth">Probably a type of ground. Usually natural, but may also apply to
            artificial preparations of soil. Duplicate of dirt.
        </item>
        <item name="grass">Grass covered ground. Mostly nice to walk. May turn into surface=dirt or
            become overgrown and disappear.
        </item>
        <item name="grass_paver">A sort of permeable paving using regular cell structure, where the
            voids in this structure enable rainwater to drain into the ground and the structure
            itself increases the load bearing capability. Often used for parking lots or infrequent
            used ways like for emergency-vehicles.
        </item>
        <item name="mud">Similar to ground but most of the year wet which gives a soft ground with
            low carrying capacity. Mostly found on wetland like swamps or in tidal areas. Sometimes
            also found on slopes draining onto a way.
        </item>
        <item name="sand">Small to very small fractions (less than 2mm) of rock.</item>
        <item name="woodchips">Woodchips as a surface, perhaps for a playground or walking trail.
            Sometimes written as wood chips.
        </item>
        <item name="snow">Winter roads surfaced with compacted snow.</item>
        <item name="ice">Ice roads, winter roads</item>
        <item name="salt">Dry salt lakes</item>
        <item name="mixed">Mixed surface types (will not be used for training)</item>
    </array>

    <array name="surface_type_photo_resources">
        <item name="paved">@drawable/empty</item>
        <item name="asphalt">@drawable/surface_type_asphalt</item>
        <item name="concrete">@drawable/surface_type_concrete</item>
        <item name="concrete:lanes">@drawable/surface_type_concrete_lanes</item>
        <item name="concrete:plates">@drawable/surface_type_concrete_plates</item>
        <item name="paving_stones">@drawable/surface_type_paving_stones</item>
        <item name="sett">@drawable/surface_type_sett</item>
        <item name="unhewn_cobblestone">@drawable/surface_type_unhewn_cobblestone</item>
        <item name="cobblestone">@drawable/surface_type_cobblestone</item>
        <item name="metal">@drawable/surface_type_metal</item>
        <item name="wood">@drawable/surface_type_wood</item>
        <item name="stepping_stones">@drawable/surface_type_stepping_stones</item>
        <item name="unpaved">@drawable/empty</item>
        <item name="compacted">@drawable/surface_type_compacted</item>
        <item name="fine_gravel">@drawable/surface_type_fine_gravel</item>
        <item name="gravel">@drawable/empty</item>
        <item name="rock">@drawable/surface_type_rock</item>
        <item name="pebblestone">@drawable/surface_type_pebblestone</item>
        <item name="ground">@drawable/surface_type_ground</item>
        <item name="dirt">@drawable/surface_type_dirt</item>
        <item name="earth">@drawable/surface_type_earth</item>
        <item name="grass">@drawable/surface_type_grass</item>
        <item name="grass_paver">@drawable/surface_type_grass_paver</item>
        <item name="mud">@drawable/surface_type_mud</item>
        <item name="sand">@drawable/surface_type_sand</item>
        <item name="woodchips">@drawable/surface_type_woodchips</item>
        <item name="snow">@drawable/empty</item>
        <item name="ice">@drawable/surface_type_ice</item>
        <item name="salt">@drawable/surface_type_salt</item>
        <item name="mixed">@drawable/empty</item>
    </array>

</resources>